Guide to the Consumer Reports. Paul Kern papers, 1943-1963 RL.11821
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Paul Kern papers
1943-1963
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11821
0.6 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Paul Kern served as Legal Counsel and a member of the Board of Directors of Consumers Union in the 1940s-1950s. The Paul Kern papers include clippings, correspondence, legal documents, pamphlets and other printed materials that primarily document Kern's work as legal counsel for Consumers Union. Issues addressed include copyright infringement and fair use of Consumers Union intellectual property; Post Office censorship relating to Consumers Union's publication on contraception and sexual health; labor relations and union negotiations; libel complaints over reviews published in Consumer Reports magazine; management and employee pension programs; and property issues relating to the Mount Vernon offices of Consumers Union. Correspondents include John J. Carson (Federal Trade Commission) and Frank Walker, Postmaster General. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Legal Files
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Paul Kern served as Legal Counsel, Secretary (1942-1943) and a member of the Board of Directors (1937-1955) of Consumers Union in the 1940s-1950s. Kern also served in the U.S. Army during World War II.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Paul Kern papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports. A.J. Isserman papers
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Board of Directors records
Collection Overview
The Paul Kern papers include clippings, correspondence, legal documents, pamphlets and other printed materials that primarily document Kern's work as legal counsel for Consumers Union. Issues addressed include copyright infringement and fair use of Consumers Union intellectual property; Post Office censorship relating to Consumers Union's publication on contraception and sexual health; labor relations and union negotiations; libel complaints over reviews published in Consumer Reports magazine; management and employee pension programs; and property issues relating to the Mount Vernon offices of Consumers Union. Correspondents include John J. Carson (Federal Trade Commission) and Frank Walker, Postmaster General.
Lawyers -- New York (State); Contraception -- United States; Real property; Pensions -- United States; Labor unions; Postal service -- Law and legislation -- United States; Censorship -- United States -- Case studies; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; United States. Post Office Department; United States. Federal Trade Commission; Kern, Paul
- General Files, 1943-1963; 1
  - Bills for services rendered, 1949-1959 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1963; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--Administrative personnel, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--John Carson (Federal Trade Commissioner), 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--Pension Plan, 1949-1958 (Box 1)
  - Labor relations, 1949-1953 (Box 1)
- Legal Files, 1943-1958; 2
  - Correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box 1)
  - Buy-Rite Club, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Copyright complaint against Buy-Rite for using Consumers Union content without permission.
  - Crosman Seed Corporation, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
    Dispute with Consumers Union over rating given to Crosman's seeds.
  - Doeskin Products, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    Dispute concerning unauthorized use of Consumers Union content and ratings in Sanapak Company (later Doeskin) product advertising, addressed in correspondence as violating notions of "fair use" of Consumers Union content.
  - Doeskin Products, 1950-1951; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Frank Walker (Postmaster General), 1943-1949 (Box 2)
    Correspondence and litigation over Consumers Union's contraception booklet
  - Labor relations, 1947-1942 (Box 2)
    Legal documents involving arbitration, complaints and strikes of unions representing Consumers Union employees
  - Pension plan, 1951-1958 (Box 2)
  - Property in Mount Vernon, 1955-1958 (Box 2)
    Leases and other documents